Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/jeff-skinner-b54338 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Financial Modeling
Asset Based Lending
Middle Market

Jeff Skinner

Senior Vice President - Structured Finance at First Midwest Bank Chicago, Illinois

Summary

Accomplished commercial lending professional with 25 years of credit underwriting, portfolio management and business development experience for sponsored and non-sponsored transactions. Career experience includes leadership of a team of investment professionals dedicated to lending to private equity owned businesses, underwriting and management of cash flow transactions as a lead administrative agent and participant, and business development responsibilities for middle market private equity clients. Experience with cash flow, ABL, broadly syndicated, and workout/distressed markets.

Experience

First Midwest Bank
Senior Vice President - Structured Finance
August 2017 - Present (3 years)
Chicago, IL

First Midwest's Structured Finance Group focuses on providing senior secured cash flow based financing for private equity owned middle market companies. Current role includes sourcing and structuring transactions from private equity clients and financing partners, and overseeing the execution and portfolio management of those investments.

GE Capital

Senior Vice President-Team Leader July 2005 - August 2017 (12 years 2 months) Chicago

- Lead a team of six investment professionals that were responsible for underwriting and managing senior secured loans focused on the software, energy, aerospace and business services sectors.
- Responsible for a portfolio of 65 borrowers consisting of \$1.3 billion in commitments, primarily private equity owned.
- Created, maintained, and modified credit policy and procedure, and monitored training and compliance of team members.

Page 1 of 2

• Evaluated and recommended investment decisions to GE investment committee.

GE Capital

Vice President - Risk Management August 2002 - August 2005 (3 years 1 month) Chicago, IL

GE Capital

7 years

Assistant Vice President / Associate - Portfolio Management and Underwriting
1997 - 2002 (5 years)
Chicago, IL

Investment Analyst 1995 - 1997 (2 years) Chicago, IL

Education

Northwestern University - Kellogg School of Management MBA, Finance, Strategy · (1999 - 2002)

Gies College of Business - University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign BS, Finance · (1991 - 1995)